你在想什么
What are you thinking about?
我在想
I was thinking about something
前几天有人跟我说的
someone said to me the other day.
当人们习惯了某种生活方式
I mean, you get used to a certain way of being.
然后
And...
是会觉得就这样了
you think we are who we are
还是会觉得能继续改变
or you think we can change?
你是说你这种人吗
What, you mean people like you?
我  你  所有人
Well, me, you, people in general.
我不知道人会不会真的改变
I don't know if anyone ever changes, really,
但总会改进  对吧
but we can evolve, right?
我们一直以来都在为此努力  不是吗
I mean, that's what we're trying to do, isn't it?
努力做更好的自己
Just become better versions of ourselves.
趴下
Get down!
胡德
Hood!
《黑吃黑》第三季 第五集
Banshee S03E05
吃点药  会缓解疼痛
Medicine will help the pain.
凯
Kai.
原谅我  凯
Forgive me, Kai.
如果我能再坚强一点
If I had only been stronger,
我就能拯救你
I could have saved you.
拯救我们两个人
Could have saved us both.
凯  你在哪里  我是艾米丽
Kai, where are you? It's Emily.
你需要马上回家
You need to come home now.
别起身
Stay down.
-你去哪儿  -不能让他们进来
- Where are you going? - Can't let them get inside.
阿尔玛  你没事吧
Alma, you good?
应该没事
I think so.
好  别起身
All right, stay down.
阿尔玛  快打开无线电
Hh Alma, get on the radio.
无线电坏了
Radio's fried.
试试电话
Try the landline.
-电话没反应  -他们在干扰  继续打
- The phones are dead. - And they're jamming cells, too. Keep trying.
胡德  胡德
Hood! Hood!
-你没事吧  -我没事
- Hey, you okay? - Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
-雷文  -我没事
- Raven? - All good.
-其他人都没事吧  -没事
- Everybody else okay? - Yeah.
-西沃恩  你没事吧  -我没事
- Siobhan, you okay? - I'm okay.
没出血  没出血
No blood. No blood.
没事吧
You okay?
我...我知道
I-- I understand that
我的样子可能有点让人不安  但...
my physical appearance may be unsettling, but...
算了
Never mind.
那是谁
Who the hell was that?
我还以为是你带来的
I thought he was with you.
-警长  放我出去  -给我闭嘴
- Sheriff, get me out. - Shut the fuck up.
换弹  集合
Load and regroup.
下一个
Next one!
-布罗克  -去弄点水  来了
- Brock. - See if we can get you some water. Yeah.
快把我从这破笼子里放出去
Get me out of is goddamn cage right now!
闭嘴  普罗科特
Shut up, Proctor.
你没看到吗  我们出了点状况
If you haven't noticed, we got a bit of a situation.
这里没有掩护
I have no cover in here!
我们的掩护都一样
You've got the same cover we all have.
如果我想进来  那几扇门可挡不住我
If I wanted to get in here, those gates wouldn't stop me.
你早就进来了是件好事
Well, it's a good thing you're already in here.
是红骨帮的人
Hey, it's the Redbones.
停车场和街道对面都是他们的人
They're spread out in the parking lot and across the street.
我们得抵挡住他们  等州警前来支援
We just need to hold them off till the state police get here.
州警不会来  电话打不出去
No, they're not coming. Phones are down.
-手机也是吗  -对
- Cells, too? - Yeah.
该死
Oh, shit.
好吧  那现在我们基本只能靠自己
All right, so we're basically on our own
来对付那帮杀人狂
against a homicidal maniac
以及十来个全副武装的暴徒
and a dozen thugs armed like a platoon.
-差不多吧  -他们到底要干嘛
- That about sums it up. - What the fuck do they want?
我不知道  但无论如何我们肯定不会喜欢
I don't know, but whatever it is, we're not gonna like it.
他们要的是我  我杀了汤米
They want me. I killed Tommy.
我才不在乎谢顿要什么  他不会如愿的
I don’t give a fuck what Chayton wants. He's not get.
雷文  西沃恩  带平民去地下室
Raven, Siobhan, get these civilians down to the basement.
好了  大家跟我们走
Okay, folks. Come with us.
咱们去个安全的地方
We're gonna take you someplace safe.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
外面怎么回事
What the hell's going on out there?
我猜他们冲破大门了
I'm guessing these gates thrown
正在重新部署  制定下一步计划
and they're regrouping, figuring out their next move.
你的下一步计划是什么
What's your next move?
不知道这些门还能挡多久
I don't know how long those
我们需要更多火力
gates are gonna last. We need more firepower.
去军械库  把能找到的都拿来
Go down to the armory, get everything you can.
这些够吗  希望你不介意  警长
Is this enough? I hope you don't mind, Sheriff;
我私自行动了
I took some initiative.
我估计时间紧迫
Figured there was no time to waste.
你就是之前给我简历的家伙  对吧
You're the guy who gave me your resume, right?
戴德郡警署的
Dade County Sheriff's Department.
是的  长官  柯特·邦克
Yes, sir. Kurt Bunker.
你丫怎么进的我们军械库  邦克
How the hell did you get into our gun locker, Bunker?
我把锁砸了
I smashed the lock.
-你被录用了  -什么
- You're hired. - What?
-谢谢  长官  -把那些枪分了
- Thank you, sir. - Get those guns and hand it out.
-不是吧  胡德  -怎么
- Serious-- Hood. - What?
-普罗科特先生怎么办  -他怎么了
- What about Mr. Proctor? - What about him?
让他待在牢房里侵犯了他的公民自由权
Keeping him in that cell is a violation to civil liberty.
那是因为他太渣了
Couldn't happen to a nicer guy.
-警长  你到底放不放他  -不放
- Sheriff, you're gonna let him out or not? - Not.
好  那就是说警长意图
Okay, so the sheriff is
让我的委托人承受生命危险
willfully endangering the life of my client.
你是法院职员  快行动起来
You're an officer of the court. Do something.
这里是战争区域  律师
Th is a war zone, Counselor.
法定诉讼程序不予适用
Due process just got blown up.
斯柏林  我有个主意
Hey, Sperling, I got an idea.
不然你也去地下室吧
Why don't you go down the basement?
没有普罗科特先生  我哪也不去
I'm not fucking going anywhere without Mr. Proctor.
好吧  邦克  给他把枪
Okay, Bunker, give him a gun.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
你也该派上点用场了
Time to make yourself useful.
我不会开枪
I don't know how to shoot that thing.
我也不会  但我会拿起枪
Well, neither do I but it's not gonna stop me.
女士  那把枪后坐力很大
Ma'am, that gun packs a powerful kick.
你是要站在这里
Are you gonna stand there
摆出一副歧视女性的嘴脸质疑我
like a total misogynist and patronize me,
还是要教教我怎么用这玩意儿
or are you gonna show me how to shoot the damn thing?
谢谢你  我又体会到婚姻的乐趣了  来吧
Thank you. I just felt married again. All right, here we go.
弹夹放这里  看到没
Magazine goes right in here, all right?
一定记得打开保险
Make sure the safety is off.
放进枪膛  然后对准  射击
One in the chamber, and just point and squeeze.
需要的话可以重复几遍  胡德  地下室
Repeat as necessary. Hood, the basement.
怎么了
What about it?
紧急出口外没有闸门
The exterior doors don't have gates on them.
邦克  穿过交火区去楼下
Bunker, through the range down the stairs.
收到  长官
I'm on it. Sir.
-艾莉森  你和...  -我才不跟这家伙一起行动
- Alison. You're going with... - I'm not going anywhere with that guy.
恕我直言  女士
With all due respect, ma'am,
我明白我的外貌让人不放心
I understand my physical appearance may be alarming--
省省吧  你这种人我见多了
Save it. I've known men like you.
我了解你这种人
I know everything about you.
你想帮助别人
Hey, you wan to help people.
下面的人正需要你的帮助
There's people down there who need your help.
那就让纳粹小子去安抚他们
Then let the Nazi calm them down.
我是在跟你说话
I'm asking you.
好吧
Fine.
不过离我远点
But keep your distance,
鉴于我是新手
and I am new with this thing,
这玩意儿说不定会走火
so it might just accidentally go off.
你没意见吧
Fair enough?
没有  长官
Yes, sir.
平民都躲在地下室了
Citizens are secure in the basement.
现在要怎么做
What do we do now?
各自散开  找好隐蔽
All right, spread out, settle in.
冲进门来的一律射杀
You shoot anything that comes through those gates.
胡德
Hood!
我在听呢
I'm listening.
比利·雷文和普罗科特都在里面
You've got Billy Raven and Proctor in there.
让他俩出来  再放了纳兹和泰特
Send them both out with Nazi and Tate,
我就放过其他人
and we'll spare the rest of you.
我想想
Let me think about.
给你两分钟
You got two minutes.
警长  你不是在认真考虑
Sheriff, you are not seriously considering
把普罗科特先生交给那个疯子吧
handing Mr. Proctor over to that psychopath?
放松  杰克逊
Relax, Jackson.
我相信警长不会忘记
I'm sure the sheriff hasn't forgotten the night
那个与此相似的夜晚
much like this one when he would have die
那晚要不是我他早就死了
if not for my intervention.
警长
Sheriff?
谢顿
Hey, Chayton.
-我不答应  -不会给你第二次机会
- Can't do it. - You won't get another chance.
是吗
Is that right?
告诉你
Tell you what.
你现在滚蛋  就放你一条生路
You leave now, I let you live.
我们会进去的  小警察
We are coming in there, cop.
也许吧  但如果你进来
Maybe, but if you do,
更多的红骨帮成员就会死
more Redbones are gonna die.
死了你弟弟还不够吗
Wasn't your little brother enough?
给我闭嘴  白人小子
Shut your mouth, white boy.
你真应该好好保护他的
You know, you really should have protected him more.
我会让你痛不欲生
I'm gonna make you suffer.
谢顿
Hey, Chayton.
给我滚
Fuck off.
如果门被弄开  我们坚持不了多久
If those gates come down, we won't last long.
还剩多少弹药
How much ammo we got left?
反正不够
Not enough.
警长  让我跟谢顿谈谈
Sheriff, let me talk to Chayton.
他不想跟你谈  比利
He doesn't want to talk to you, Billy.
-他想杀了你  -我可以结束这一切
- He wants to kill you. - I could end this.
怎么结束  牺牲你自己吗
What, by sacrificing yourself?
-这是部落的规矩  -这是狗屁
- It's tribal justice. - No, bullshit is what it is.
要死一起死
We go down, we go down together.
这下糟了
Well, this sucks.
-谁要手电  西沃恩  -我抽屉里有
- Who needs a light? Siobhan? - I got one in my drawer.
-比利  你有手电吗  -有
- Billy? You got it? - Got it.
-布罗克  -拿着这个  走吧
- Hey, Brock! - Here, take it. Go.
应急照明灯呢
Where's the emergency lights?
-我们没有应急照明灯  -真棒
- We don't have emergency lights. - Perfect.
-操  都蹲下  -见鬼了
- Fuck. Stay down. - Shit.
你是在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
谢顿不久就会想出办法
At some point Chayton is gonna wise up
他会把门弄开
and he's gonna pull those gates off the hinges.
然后把你生吞活剥了
And then he's gonna eat you alive.
我可以把你送出去给他当开胃菜啊
I could always send you out there as an appetizer.
是啊
Yeah.
我宁愿在外面为了活命放手一搏
Well, I'd rather fight for my life out there
也不愿像你们一样  在黑暗中等死
than wait in the dark to die like the rest of you.
他说的有道理
He's got a point.
胡德  听着
Hood, listen.
地下室里有备用发电机
There's a backup generator in the basement.
不能完全恢复供电  但能有照明
Won't power everything, but it'll buy us some light.
-我去  -好的
- I'll go. - Okay.
-是谁  -西沃恩
- Who's there? - Siobhan.
他们把灯都关了
They took out the lights.
故意吓唬我们
They're trying to mess with our heads.
的确起效了
Well, it's working.
好了  挺好  有人听到了枪声
All right, listen. Someone heard that gunfire.
所以州警已经在来的路上了
Okay? So the state police, they're on the way.
在他们到这之前  希望你们可以团结起来
Till they get here, I need you to hang tight.
能做到吗
Can you do that?
很好
Good.
西沃恩  来处理发电机
Siobhan, take care of that generator.
没动静吧
All quiet?
目前是的  长官
So far, sir.
你一直这么有礼貌吗
You always so polite?
紧张的时候才这样
Only when I'm nervous.
-挺住  邦克  -是  长官
- Hang in there, Bunker. - Yes, sir.
-该死  -没有油了吗
- Oh, shit. - Out of gas?
就一点儿了  给  举着
Almost. Here, hold this.
他妈的
God damn it.
-你举着  我来  -不用  我可以
- Here, let me try. - No, I got it.
-给我  -我说了我可以
- Come on. - I said I got it!
这倒霉日子简直倒霉到家
This fucking day just keeps getting worse.
你觉得我是什么感觉
How do you think I feel?
我都要退休了
I was about to retire.
你是个混蛋
You're an asshole.
对
Yeah.
你都不知道你在这干嘛
You don't even know what you're doing here.
甚至都不是警察
You're not even a cop.
对  我不是
No, I'm not.
那我们他妈的为什么要听你的
Then why the fuck are we all listening to you?
知道吗
You know what?
你说得对
You're right.
但我经历过更恐怖的事
But I've been in tighter spots than this
而我还活着
and I'm still here.
所以我需要你相信我
So I need you to trust me.
你知道那听起来有多可笑吗
Do you have any idea how ridiculous that sounds?
知道
Yes.
我不想死在今晚
I don't want to die tonight.
你不会死的
You're not going to.
我们会一起走出去的
We're all walking out of this together.
我们再试一遍
Let's try it again.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
这已经不是第一次了  知道吗
This isn't the first time this has happened, you know?
一伙带着机关枪的人已经够糟了
I mean, one army of guys with machine guns would be bad enough.
结果来两伙  简直是...
But two? I mean, that's just...
霉运当头
Bad luck?
不  不是这样的
No, it's something else.
天啊
Jesus.
-给  -谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
这里太安静了
It's so quiet in here.
你觉得他们走了吗
You think they left?
谢顿不会离开的
Chayton's not going anywhere.
不达目的不会离开
Not till he gets what he wants.
不  他们会很快就离开的
No, they'll make a move soon.
希望我...
Wish I had-- -
斯柏林
Sperling!
你他妈在干嘛
What the hell are you doing?
我在帮我的委托人脱离危险
I'm getting my client out of harm's way.
钥匙给我  杰克逊
Give me the keys, Jackson.
-见鬼  -趴下
- Blow me. - Get down!
-操  -他妈的快把钥匙给我  杰克逊
- Shit! - Give me the fucking keys, Jackson.
-滚开  艾莉森  -快把钥匙给我
- Fuck off, Alison. - Give me the fucking keys!
过来  过来
Hey, hey. Come on. Come on.
雷文在哪
Where's Raven?
-布罗克  雷文在哪  -那边
- Brock, where's Raven? - In there.
-瑞文  -在这里
- Raven! - Yeah?
掩护我
Cover me!
-趴下  趴下  -快跑  隐蔽
- Down! Down! - Come on, move! Take cover!
我们得把缺口堵上
Let's get this hole covered up.
普罗科特在哪
Where's Proctor?
显然他的律师把他放跑了
Apparently his lawyer got him an early release.
-什么  -帮我一下  帮我
- What? - Help me. Help me.
坚持住
Come on.
那些撑不了多久的
Those aren't gonna hold them off for long.
没错  但比什么都没有强
No, but it's better than nothing.
-那是什么声音  -不知道  呆在这
- What is that? - I don't know. Stay here.
开始吧
Let's do it.
你会找我麻烦吗
We gonna have a problem?
不  今晚不会
No, not tonight.
主祷文念诵
像我们宽恕我们的敌人一样
As we forgive those who trespass against us.
不教我们遇见试探
And lead us not into temptation,
救我们脱离恶者
but deliver us from evil.
因为国度
For Thine is the kingdom,
权力和荣耀
the power and the glory,
都属于你  直到永远
forever and ever.
阿门
Amen.
上  上
Go! Go!
-散开散开  -快  快
- Stand clear! - Move! Move!
快灭火
Put it out!
我能感觉到你在看着我
I can feel you looking at me.
-你还好吗  -我没事  不用担心
- Are you okay? - I'm fine. Don't worry about it.
我不是你想象的那种人
I'm not who you think I am.
是吗  可不是吗
Oh, really? Right.
-我猜你变了  -是的
- I guess you've changed. - Yes.
人是不会变的
People don't change.
我16岁的时候
When I was 16,
亲眼看着我父亲被两个
I watched my father beaten into a coma
和你一样的男人殴打  昏迷
by two men who looked just like you.
你知道那是什么感觉吗
Do you have any idea what that feels like?
看着自己的父亲渺小无助鲜血淋淋的
To watch your father helpless and bleeding,
求着两个恶棍放过他唯一的女儿
begging two thugs to spare his only daughter.
他们没有
They didn't.
没放过我
You know, spare me.
那你说  邦克
So tell me, Bunker,
是什么让一个男人充满仇恨
what fills a man with so much hate
以至于他把这些仇恨永久的纹满全身
that he has to permanently paint it all over his body?
向全世界宣告他的仇恨
Announce to the world that he hates something that much?
我父亲曾是我生活中最强大的男人
My father was the biggest man I ever knew.
我小的时候他经常打我
He beat me a lot when I was a kid,
所以我尽量不回家
so I stayed away from home as much as possible.
以前我有点结巴  很严重
I had a stutter, a really bad one,
所以我也很少说话
so I didn't talk much either.
我家附近有一个叫汤克的邻居
There was this guy in our neighborhood, Tank.
块头很大  是个全身纹身的恶棍
Big and badass and covered in tattoos.
每次他看见我  都会陪我坐着
And every time he saw me, he would sit me down
还给我买汽水喝
and buy me a soda.
告诉我  我有力量来改变这些
Tell me that I had the power to change things.
他把我介绍给他的弟兄们
Introduced me to his buddies.
只有他们让我觉得还有人在意我的存在
They were the only people that made me feel like I mattered.
有一天  我的父亲把我的眼睛打青了
One day, my father gave me a black eye.
我不记得原因了  但是汤克看到了
I don't remember why, but Tank saw it.
他送我回家
He marched me home,
掐住我父亲的喉咙
he grabbed my father by the throat,
逼他道歉
made him apologize.
让他保证再也不会动我一根汗毛
Made him promise he would never do it again.
他说  你儿子现在是我们的一员了
He said, "Your boy is one of us now."
我父亲再也没敢动过我一下
My father never laid a hand on me again.
我第一次觉得自己有了力量
For the first time I had power.
在我意识到之前
And before I knew it...
就已经成为其中一员了
I had become one of them.
不要找任何借口
That is no goddamn excuse.
我明白
I know that.
我当然明白
放下枪  普罗科特
Drop it, Proctor!
不用  布罗克  没关系
No, Brock, it's okay.
去你的
The hell it is.
放下你的武器  给我放下
Now drop your weapon. Drop it!
-别用你的枪指着我  -我让你放下枪
- Get that fucking gun out of my face. - I said drop it!
我跟你是一个战线的
I'm on your side!
冷静点  外面的才是敌人
Hey, hey, hey! The fight's out there.
一个小时前  你用锤子
An hour ago, I stopped you
揍这个混蛋被我阻止了
from braining this asshole with a fucking hammer.
现在你想让他为所欲为吗
Now you're letting him do whatever the hell he wants?
在我的地盘上可不行
No. Not in my house.
这不是你的地盘
It's not your house.
-这就是我的底盘  -别他妈的碰我
- It is my fucking house! - Don't you fucking touch me.
你他妈的给了普罗科特一把枪
You gave Proctor a goddamn gun.
你是不是在逗我
Are you kidding me?
他本来就有枪  我给了他些子弹
He had the gun. I gave him some ammo.
-为什么  -因为需要援助
- Why? - Because we need all the help we can get.
不不不  我不稀罕他的帮助
No, no, no. I don't want his help.
我不需要他的帮助
I don't need his help.
我要把这个杀人犯关在监狱里
I want that murderer locked up in a cell.
-这才是我要的  -这是我下的命令
- That's what I need. - It was my call and I made it.
是  这的确是你的命令
Yeah, of course it was your call.
无视法律  无视规则
You know, forget the law, forget the rules.
想怎么做就怎么做
Just make it up as you go, huh?
-你冷静点  -去你的
- Hey, just calm down. - No, fuck that!
不断有人在丧命
People are dying
接下来可能是我们其中一个
and any one of us could be next.
-听我说  -你知道吗
- Listen to me. - No, you know what?
事实就是你每次行动仓促
The fact is you go off half-cocked whenever it suits you
我们还要在后面给你擦屁股
and the rest of us just have to fight your battles.
我受够了  我以后再也不会听从你
Well, I'm done. I've had it, I'm not listening to you anymore.
好啊  可以  把你的徽章还给我
All right, fine. Give me your fuckin' badge.
我的徽章
My badge?
知道吗  在你来之前
You know, before you got here,
我兢兢业业的工作
I did this job by the book.
付出了很多时间
I put in my time,
还因此和老婆离了婚
I sacrificed my marriage for this job
就因为这是我的长处
because I'm good at it.
我干警察干得很好
I'm good at being a cop.
会杀人不代表能胜任这份工作
Being good at killing people doesn't make you right for this job.
是吗
Is that right?
因为你杀人杀的也不错啊
'Cause you're pretty fucking good at doing that, too.
是  是的  我试过了
Yeah. Yeah. I did. I tried.
我试过了  胡德
I tried, Hood.
我试着按你的方式来做事
I tried doing things your way.
我说服我自己这是最正确的
I convinced myself it was for the best,
但你所到之处血流成河
but everything you touch turns to blood.
带大家去另一间房
Get everyone in the other room now!
快快  出去  去另一间房
Go, go! Get out! Other room, go!
快  快  快
Go, go, go!
要命
Fuck.
你没事吧
Hey, you all right?
没事  不要担心我  守住门
Yeah, don't worry about me. Just cover the door.
不断有人丧命
People are dying.
你所到之处血流成河
Everything you touch turns to blood.
你连自己在做什么都不知道
You don't even know what you're doing here.
你不配当个警察
You're not even a cop.
-我要出去  -你说什么
- I'm going out there. - What the hell are you talking about?
必须有人去确认支援已经来了
Someone's gotta make sure help is on the way.
胡德  这简直是自杀
Hood, it's suicide.
他说的没错  你会死在外面的
He's right, you'll die out there.
你连站都站不稳
You can barely even stand.
我们拖延不了多久
We can't hold them off forever.
想个别的办法
Find another way.
我去
I'll go.
一旦我们安全了  我就寻求帮助
Once we're clear, I'll call for help.
你不会安全的  30秒内你就要死了
You won't get clear. You'll be dead inside of 30 seconds.
不管怎样都是你赢  副警长
Well, either way you win, Deputy.
听着  你被捕了  普罗科特
You know what? You're under arrest, Proctor.
不准你走出这扇门
You don't get to just walk out this door.
没退路了
Desperate times.
没错吧  警长
Right, Sheriff?
一路顺风
Godspeed.
如果我死了
If I don't make it outta here,
你他妈的离丽贝卡越远越好
you stay the fuck away from Rebecca.
好的
Okay.
如果我活下来
If I do make it,
你我的事还没完
you and I have unfinished business.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
冲出去了别忘了打电话
Don't forget to make that call.
好了  我们走
Come on. Let's go.
堵上这扇门
Let's block up this door.
现在还不晚  丽贝卡
It's not too late, Rebecca.
离开这里
Leave this house.
自求谋生
Find your own way.
雷文守着大房间
Raven's covering the bullpen.
布罗克和邦克在楼下守门
Brock's downstairs watching the door with Bunker.
好的
Okay.
你觉得普罗科特做到了吗
You think Proctor made it?
做到了
I do.
我们拥有的一切
What we had...
有真实的吗
was any of it real?
所有都是
All of it.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你被关了多久
How long were you locked up?
十五年
15 years.
天呐
Oh, my God.
然后你到这儿发现卡莉找了戈登养儿育女
And then you come here and Carrie's got Gordon and the kids.
没错
That's right.
那现在呢
And now?
你真的就想这么一走了之吗
Would you really just have walked away?
如果你想的话
If that's what you want.
如果我不想呢
What if it isn't?
那我俩一起走
Then we leave together.
我了解你的一切了吗
Do I know everything about you?
没有
Not yet.
但如果你想
But if you want to...
你就会了解
you will.
好的
Okay.
那你先告诉我你的真名
Start by telling me your real name.
雷文
比利
Billy.
你在搞什么
What the hell are you doing?
-我要终结这一切  -赶快离开那里
- I'm ending this. - Get away from there!
我必须这么做
I have to do this.
只能这样了
It's the only way.
切顿
Chayton.
雷文
Raven.
必须了结这一切
This has to end.
你知道会付出什么代价
You know what it'll take.
以血还血
Blood for blood.
我主动投降
I give myself up.
你撤回你的人
You call off your men.
放过这儿的人
You leave these people alone.
谈判已经结束了
The time for negotiating has passed.
他们都得付出代价
They'll all pay now.
天呐
For Christ's sakes.
难道你还没杀够吗
Haven't you killed enough people already?
坚持住
Come on.
坚持住  比利  我扶你离开这里
Come on, Billy, we gotta get you outta here.
坚持住
Come on.
等一会
Here, hold on.
-伤口有多糟  -只是需要止住血
- How bad? - Just have to stop the bleeding.
他能站起来吗
Can he stand?
可以
Yeah. Yeah.
扶他起来  要去地下室
Get him up. Gotta go to the basement.
操  快来
Fuck. Come on, come on, come on.
你快去吧  我们就在你后面
No, just go. Just go, we'll be right behind you.
-不  快走  -你先走
- No, come on. - Just go.
去吧
Go.
我们会没事的
We'll be okay.
好吧
Okay.
-腿不受控制了  -你会休克的
- I can't control my legs. - You're going into shock.
-你需要到楼下去  -我不会留下你独自在这里的
- You need to get downstairs. - I'm not leaving you here.
西沃恩
Siobhan.
过来
Come here.
我杀了汤米
I killed Tommy.
这是血债血偿
It's blood for blood.
比利  看着我  听着
Billy, look at me. Listen.
你在萨沃伊救了我的命
You saved my life at the Savoy.
你不会因此而死的
You're not gonna die for that.
我没弹药了
I have no ammo.
给你
Here.
以防万一我没机会说了
In case I don't get a chance,
-我只想说  -别这样
- I just want to say-- - Don't do that.
-别怎么样  -别做你想的
- Do what? - What you're about to do.
我只是想说
I was just gonna say
我仍然觉得我当警长会比你好
I still think I would have been a better sheriff than you.
嗯  你大概是对的
Yeah, you're probably right.
我们应该去追他们吗
Should we go after them?
请便
Help yourself.
放开她  切顿
Let her go, Chayton.
我说了  放开她
I said, let her go.
妈的  你快放开她不然我打爆你的头
God damn it, you let her go or I'll blow your fucking head off!
不  不
No. No.
不  不  切顿
No, no, no, Chayton. Chayton.
住手  好吗
Just stop, okay?
这跟她一点儿关系都没有
This has got nothing to do with her.
明白了
All right?
求你了
Please.
这是你我之间的事
It's between you and me.
放她走
Just let her go.
-不  -求你了
- No. - Please.
不
No.
求你了
Please.
Please. Please.
上帝  我们的天父
God, our Father...
您的力量带给了我们生命
Your power brings us to birth.
我们根据您的旨意活着
Your providence guides our lives.
在你的要求下  我们回归尘土
And by Your command, we return to dust.
主  已故之人
Lord, those who die
仍活在您的国
still live in Your presence.
变了样子  但依然活着
Their lives change, but do not end.
我为我的家人
I pray and hope for my family,
亲戚和朋友们
relatives, and friends,
以及所有天国中的逝者向您祷告
and for all the dead known to You alone.
与耶稣同在
In company with Christ,
-逝者和生者  -西沃恩
- who died and now lives... - Siobhan?
愿他们都在您的天国里重聚
...may they all rejoice in His kingdom,
那里没有泪水和悲伤
where all our tears are wiped away.
西沃恩
Siobhan?
使我们重聚在大家庭中
Unite us together again in one family...
-嗨  -一起永远唱主的赞歌
- Hey, hey. - ...to sing His praise fever and ever.
阿门
Amen.
天哪
Oh, my... Oh, my... Oh, my...